Rebecca (Green) Ravenoak (pronouns: they/them)
rebeccaravenoak@gmail.com • rebeccamgreen.com • (408) 835-4506
https://github.com/ggggbbybby

I am a full-stack software engineer with 10+ years of experience working with Ruby and Javascript. I enjoy collaborating with non-technical users to build friendly and efficient systems and I give excellent, clear answers to tricky technical questions. I care about accessibility, performance, and collaboratio. I prefer small teams and the flexibility that comes with them.

Education

B.S. Computer Science, Concentration in Philosophy, Harvey Mudd College, 2011

Work Experience

key themes - internal tools, test-driven development, well-documented systems, delightful UX

Senior Software Engineer, Trim by OneMain, Remote (Sept 2021 - present)

- * I build, maintain, debug, and demystify our negotiation data pipelines, enabling operations to manage their resources effectively and ensuring the best user experience possible.
- * I mentor other engineers, provide technical feedback on their proposals and review their code for robustness, performance, accessibility, and maintainability.

Senior Software Engineer, Datagrail, San Francisco, CA (Jan 2020 - June 2020)

- * Refactored API integrations to improve interoperability between complex customer systems
- * Designed and built prototypes for customer data summaries for GDPR and CCPA compliance

Senior Software Engineer - Data Tools, Slack, San Francisco, CA (May 2018 - Oct 2019)

- * Built and optimized internal analytics dashboards in React
- * Created in-depth documentation for advanced dashboard features and A/B test framework
- * Implemented real-time pipelines using Kafka for viewing A/B test data within seconds

Senior Software Engineer, LendingHome, San Francisco, CA (Sept 2015 - April 2018)

- * Expanded and optimized workflow prioritization algorithms & work items for loan officers.
- * Built MVP for consumer mortgage loan product on a tight deadline.
- * Created and expanded testing tools for Automation and Manual Testing

Older work experiences elided to save space, details available on my website

- Full-Stack Engineer, BrightBytes, San Francisco, CA (Oct 2014 Sept 2015)
- Back-End Engineer, Glyde, Palo Alto, CA (July 2011 Oct 2014)